# Ogooluwa Olutimilehin

WEB DEVELOPER

An enthusiastic web developer with hands-on experience in creating interactive and responsive web applications, translating designs, interacting with Rest APIs, code versioning and using external libraries to create rich interfaces. Able to effectively self-manage during independent projects, as well as collaborate as part of a productive team.

+234 912 101 7814

extremeworkbench@gmail.com

Lagos, Nigeria





**GitHub** 

# Experience

#### Junior Web Developer

Glam's Haven | 2020 - 2021

- Reduced customer support requests by 25% through the implementation of effective user feedback processes.
- Developed applications using React while managing the State through Redux and Redux-Forms saving 5+ hours of users' time.
- Increased web traffic by 23% through the development of engaging and effective user experiences.
- Developed user interfaces with modern JavaScript frameworks(React), HTMLS, TailwindCss and SCSS, which improved user satisfaction by 47%.

#### **Junior Software Engineer**

Securesoft Limited | 2022 - now

- Engaged in new business development, from a technical reference point in order to boost functionality and use-cases of software.
- Curated over 50 website changes to increase the user flow and understanding of all platform capabilities and features.
- Engaged in 100+ hours of Laravel training and PHP crash course with lead Technical officer.
- Assisted in product development and enhancements of current suite to boost engagement by 15%.
- Provided technical support for 10+ existing online products.

#### Education

#### **Bachelors in Information Technology**

Eastern Mediterranean University | Bsc. Graduated with High Honors

#### PERSONAL PROJECTS

(visit <a href="https://ogooluwanick-portfolio.netlify.app/">https://ogooluwanick-portfolio.netlify.app/</a>)

#### **Inventools - Graduation Project**

March 2021 - January 2022

- Created a database with MongoDB
- Created user login and registration
- Inventory functionality and Categorization for with using React Hooks
- Page Routing using React Router
- · Utilized node/express for the backend
- Used Semantic UI for the dashboard/and data tables.
- Used CSS/SASS for styling and User Interface design.

## **Echos - Blog Webapp**

i January 2022 - February 2022

- Created a database with MongoDB
- · Made use of Google api for automatic login
- Created custom user login and registration.
- Made use of Redux for state management.
- · Page Routing using React Route.
- Utilized node/express for the backend.
- Used Material UI for the most major styling.
- · Used SASS to make the site responsive

# **CURRENT INTERESTS**

- React-native
- Micro Frontend Architecture
- Web3
- Data Analysis with Python

### Skills

- HTML
- CSS/SCSS/SASS
- JavaScript
- ReactJs
- React-Native
- Redux (Redux Toolkit)
- · Git & Github
- Bootstrap/ TailwindCss
- Laravel
- Data Visualisation (recharts, chart.js)
- Front-End Development

#### **Licenses & Certifications**

- Responsive Web Design
  - Issued May 2022 · No Expiration Date
  - Credential ID fcc971fa9f7-36ac-48d3-931e-537e2125f000
- Front End Development Libraries
  - o Issued July 2022 · No Expiration Date
  - Credential ID fcc971fa9f7-36ac-48d3-931e-537e2125f000
- Fundamentals of digital marketing
  - $\circ~$  Issued Apr 2022  $\cdot$  No Expiration Date
  - Credential ID PJN S8K V4K

# **DEPLOYMENT - CI/CD**

- Netlify
- AWS